

1160 Hilary Lane, Highland Park, IL 60035

□ (847) 722-4850 | ■ aaronlichtman@gmail.com | 回 alichtman | 🛅 aaron-lichtman

## Summary.

Highly motivated, capable software engineer with over 3 years of hands-on experience, including industry work on the Wayfair iOS Core team. Specializing in computational linguistics, backend/infrastructure, and data analysis, with an interest in computer security.

## **Honors & Awards**

Best Healthcare-related OSS Hack (TypeSense), HackIllinois Champaign, IL 2017, 2018 Dean's List, University of Illinois Champaign, IL AP Scholar with Distinction, Highland Park High School Highland Park, IL 2016 Highland Park Honors Society, Highland Park High School Highland Park, IL

### **Education**

#### **University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign**

**B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND LINGUISTICS** 

- · 3.74/4.00 GPA
- · Business Minor
- · Relevant Coursework: Discrete Structures, Data Structures, Computer Architecture, Computational Linguistics

**Mobile Makers Academy** Chicago, IL

MOBILE IOS DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP

- Summer 2015
- Three-week intensive iOS mobile application development program focusing on Swift. Collaborated with a team to develop an educational game about algorithmic thinking.

# **Experience**

#### iOS Core Developer - Summer Internship

Boston, MA

Champaign, IL

Aug. 2016 - May 2020

WAYFAIR

Summer Internship 2018

- Working on a team to integrate iMessage sharing of "idea boards" into the Wayfalr iOS app.
- Furthering my UI/UX design skills after learning best practices for designing a smooth, intuitive experience for iOS app users.
- Learning Swift 4 and the intricacies of the UIKit framework

#### **Course Infrastructure Developer - Plagiarism Detection Software**

Champaign, IL

University of Illinois - College of Engineering

Jan. 2018 - Present

- Developing software that combines behavioral indicators with code structure and style metrics to detect plagiarism.
- Learned to use the ANTLRv4 and NLTK libraries as powerful tools for language recognition and code parsing.

#### Stronghold - macOS Security Configuration Tool

Champaign, IL

Personal Software Development Project

May 2017

- Designed, developed, and open-sourced a command line app in Python that walked the user through a secure macOS configuration process.
- Provided active support for the over 4000 users logged to date.

#### **Lab Instructor for Intro to Computer Science**

Champaign, IL

University of Illinois - College of Engineering

Aug. 2017 - Dec. 2017

- Taught fundamentals of Java programming and algorithm analysis in weekly two-hour lab sections.
- Worked one-on-one with students during office hours; moderated course forum.

## Extracurriculars\_

#### Leadership Training as Link Crew Leader and Assistant Instructor

Highland Park, IL

LINK CREW LEADERSHIP PROGRAM

- Completed a year-long leadership training program, earning my Red Cross lifeguard certification.
- Led high school orientation programs for incoming freshmen.

2015-2016

#### **Foreign Exchange Programs**

San Sebastian, Spain Summers 2013-2017

FOREIGN EXCHANGE STUDENT AND HOST

• Lived with a family in San Sebastian, Spain for three summers and learned conversational Spanish at Lacunza Academy.

- Hosted multiple exchange students from Spain during high school.
- Traveled throughout Israel on Birthright and private trips.

# **Skills**

**Development Skills** Data structures, optimization, algorithms, UI/UX design, software testing, debugging.

**Languages** Python, Swift, C++, Java (incl. Android), MIPS, Verilog, HTML, CSS. **Software** JetBrains IDEs, XCode, Android Studio, Git, Sketch, Command Line.